Are men able to dance?
男人会跳舞吗？
Well, if I am an example, then no – I have two left feet and taking to the dance floor just fills me with dread.
嗯，如果以我为例的话，答案是否定的——我跳舞时笨手笨脚，一去舞池就充满了恐惧（dread）。
But of course, we know that most of us have the potential to throw some shapes, so what is it that's stopping us?
但当然，我们知道我们大多数人都有展示舞姿的潜力，那么是什么阻止了我们呢？
If you've ever watched glamorous and glitzy dance shows on TV, like the BBC's Strictly Come Dancing, you'll know that there are men who have great dexterity and fancy footwork on the dancefloor.
如果你曾经在电视上看过迷人又炫目的舞蹈节目，比如BBC的《舞动奇迹》（Strictly Come Dancing），你就会知道，有些男人在舞池里舞步花俏且灵活，和花式的舞步。
These professional dancers have spent years learning and performing ballroom dances such as the waltz, foxtrot and tango.
这些专业舞者花了数年时间学习和表演华尔兹、狐步舞和探戈等交际舞。
But for a majority of us men, we still prefer to spectate rather than participate.
但对于我们大多数男人来说，我们仍然更喜欢观看（spectate）而不是参与。
And according to a survey commissioned by BBC Radio 5 live, over three quarters of British men have never or rarely danced.
根据BBC第五电台（BBC Radio 5 live）委托进行的一项调查，超过四分之三的英国男人从未或很少跳舞。
It found that over a third of men surveyed wouldn't strut their stuff, let alone perform a paso doble, on the dancefloor because they were too embarrassed.
调查发现，超过三分之一的受访男性因为太尴尬而不会在舞池里炫耀自己的本领（strut their stuff），更别提跳斗牛舞（paso doble）了。
And ten per cent said what put them off was fear of being the centre of attention, being made fun of, or being judged.
10%的人表示，让他们排斥的原因是害怕成为关注的焦点、被人取笑或被人评判。
Women may say we have to get a grip, get on our feet and just let ourselves go!
女人们可能会说我们得掌控局面，站起来，尽情释放自己！
Easier said than done.
说起来容易做起来难。
But what helps is a crowded dancefloor where there is safety in numbers.
但有帮助的是一个拥挤的舞池，人多就有安全感。
And according to the survey, many men need a drink.
而且根据调查，很多男人需要喝点酒壮胆。
One man questioned said, "I don't think I'm very good at it and therefore need some Dutch courage to get me on the floor."
一位接受调查的男士说：“我觉得我不太擅长跳舞，所以需要酒后之勇（Dutch courage）才能让我走上舞池。”
One place where the alcohol is flowing is usually at a wedding, so, maybe unsurprisingly, the BBC survey found that 75% of men had previously danced at one.
通常有一个地方酒是畅饮的，那就是婚礼上，所以，也许并不奇怪，BBC的调查发现75%的男人以前在婚礼上跳过舞。
These are also the situations where partners of boyfriends and husbands can persuade them to move to the groove of the music!
在这种情况下，男朋友或丈夫的女伴们也可以说服他们随着音乐的节奏舞动起来！
However, this is the time to witness some 'dad dancing' which is defined in the Oxford English Dictionary as: "An awkward, unfashionable, or unrestrained style of dancing to pop music, as characteristically performed by middle-aged or older men."
然而，这时就可能会看到一些“老爸式舞蹈”，《牛津英语词典》对其的定义是：“一种在流行音乐伴奏下笨拙、不时髦或无拘无束的舞蹈风格，典型的是由中年或年龄更大的男人跳的。”
Surely that's not me!
当然，那说的肯定不是我！
So let's face it, us men just need help.
所以，让我们面对现实吧，我们男人就是需要帮助。
We need training, we need to practise and we need to lose our inhibitions.
我们需要训练，需要练习，还需要放下拘谨。
One convert, Gareth Dew, who took part in the survey, says, "I think to be able to dance you need to be able to let loose, be aware of your body and generally be more comfortable in yourself."
一位参与调查并刚迷上跳舞的人，加雷思・迪尤（Gareth Dew）说：“我认为要想会跳舞，你得能够放松，了解自己的身体，并且总体上让自己更自在。”
Would you agree?
你同意吗？